ESRA AL-ABDULJABAR

Oakville, Ontario

Phone: 6043387943 | Email: abduljabaresra0@gmail.com

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/esra-software-dev | GitHub: https://github.com/EsraWameed | Portfolio:

https://esrawameed.github.io/Esra-Personal-Portfolio/

SUMMARY

Full stack Web Developer with a background in Biology and Secondary Mathematics/Science Education. Effective team collaborator through the use of task organization and prioritization and GitHub project boards. Known among team for trouble shooting errors, resolving deployement errors, and creating a smooth user experience.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, jQuery, Node.js, MySQL,MongoDB, Express.js, React.js, Bootstrap, Materialize

Applications: VS Code, Atom, Slack, Heroku, Git, GitHub, GitLab, Figma, Hyper, Insomnia, Postman, Studio 3T, MongoDB Compass.

PROJECTS

Teagram https://github.com/EsraWameed/teagram/https://esrawameed.github.io/Motivation-Locale/

- **Project Summary:** A RESTful API social media application allowing users to create profiles and interact with other users posts through liking, commenting, and downloading images.
- **Responsibilities:** Initialized remote GitHub repo, protected main branch, created Sequelize models/associations,handled requests, and used proof of concept for updating user profile images.
- <u>Tools / languages:</u> HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node.js, Express.js(fileUpload, session, handlebars), MySQL, Sequelize ORM, MVC, Dotenv, Bcrypt.

Motivation Locale https://github.com/EsraWameed/Motivation-Locale/https://esrawameed.github.io/Motivation-Locale/

- **Project Summary:** An application utilizing two server-side API's to randomly generate motivational quotes, positive images, and store user feelings to lift user spirit.
- **Responsibilities:** Led project through initializing GitHub repo, protecting main branch through review before merge. Added functionality for fetching images from Type.fit API and making this generation random
- <u>Tools / languages:</u> HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Materialize, GitHub, Chrome DevTools, VS Code, Stack Overflow.

App-Weather- https://github.com/EsraWameed/WeatherBoard https://esrawameed.github.io/WeatherBoard/

- **Project Summary:** An application utilizing third-party APIs to retrieve daily weather data. Upon a user searching for a city, weather data, and a 5-day forecast are saved into localStorage.
- **Responsibilities:** Made requests to a third-party API, 5 Day Weather Forecast to retrieve data of the city searched by the user, as well as the 5 day forecast. Data was locally stored.
- <u>Tools / languages:</u> HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Moment.js

EXPERIENCE

SuperPROF, Private Lessons Directory

Remote

Guided students through web development concepts through hands-on, interactive, project based tutoring sessions. Students came out of each session with their own personally generated code.

Remote Mathematics Course Developer - Grade 11/12 New Oriental International College

2021 – 2022 Markham, ON

Utilized curriculum development experience and technical skills with LMS to develop asynchronous Math courses that included scaffolded lessons, engaging activities, video explanations, and formative/summative assessments allowing students to focus on one place for all the resources they need to succeed.

- Initially hired as a remote Mathematics/Science Teacher but was offered a new contract as an instructor and a course developer after updating assessment rubrics to better meet curricular expectations.
- Converted modules from outdated PDF and directly built them onto Canvas which expedited the grading process as it was adopted across the Math department.

Remote Mathematics and Science Teacher - Grade 10/11 New Oriental International College

2021 – 2022 Markham, ON

Planned lessons strategically through organizing content in a way that builds on student prior knowledge maximized student learning through giving quick feedback on homework and assignments which allowed students to implement changes and seed help prior to summative assessments.

 Led Unit review sessions and encouraged students to collaborate in group activities to learn from each other.

Remote Learning Mathematics Teacher - Grade 7 New Oriental International College

2020 – 2021 MapleRidge, BC

Coordinated a remote learning program for children of immunocompromised families comprising of full class Zoom meetings, small groups, and individual office hour times to ensure the needs of all students are being met.

- Monitored the progress of 60 students through using the LMS, Moodle.
- Communicated consistently with the families of students to device success plans as a team.

EDUCATION

Full Stack Web Developement Bootcamp

Certificate: University of Toronto, Toronto, ON, Canada

A 12-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js, and ReactJS.

Bachelor of Education in Secondary Mathematics/Science

Degree: University of the Fraser Valley, Abbotsford, BC, Canada

Bachelor of Science majoring in Biology

Degree: University of the Fraser Valley, Abbotsford, BC, Canada